

## Frank Gaete

frank.gaete1@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/frankgaete/



# Education

### **B.A. Social Science**

Adelphi University, Garden City

#### Certificate

Internet Architecture at Hofstra University, Uniondale

#### Certificate

Client Server Systems at Dowling College, Oakdale

### Skills

UI/UX Design
PC/Mac
Adobe XD, Creative Suite
Figma
UX Research
HTML, CSS
Ideation, collaboration
Agile, Jira

# Military Experience

US Army Reserve. Highest Rank: Sergeant. Honorable Discharge

### **Interests**

Tennis

Guitar

Movies, music

Travel

Boating

Family & friends

### Summary

I am a UI/UX designer with over 26 years of experience across numerous verticals and organizations ranging from small startups to global fortune 500. I strongly advocate user centered design, UX research, cross team collaboration; design consistency, and delivery of optimized user experiences.

### **Work Experience**

### TD Bank, Sr. UX Designer

Aug 2021 – present, Remote

- Design interfaces and experiences for client facing products and services
- Develop wireframes, visual designs, user flows/journeys using Figma, Adobe XD
- Plan and design UX research goals and prototypes; analyze data to guide design enhancement recommendations
- Collaborate with pod members (PO, scrum master, devs, QA, content and others); cross team members and enterprise UX designers to ensure consistency across products and platforms

### NextEra/Florida Power & Light, Sr. UX Design & Research

Jan 2020 – Jul 2021, Jupiter FL

- Designed interfaces and experiences for nuclear power enterprise applications
- Planned and executed UX research; analyze data to guide design enhancement recommendations; help standardize UX research methods and processes for future testing
- Developed new design patterns and workflows using Adobe XD, Sketch, and UXpin
- Collaborated with nuclear team members; product owners and enterprise UX designers

### Clever Devices, Sr. UX Architect

Sep 2017 – Dec 2019, Woodbury NY

- Designed interfaces and experiences across several major product groups for desktop, responsive and mobile applications as per requirements, business goals and user research
- Promoted the value of UX research; defined and executed research processes and methodologies to drive design enhancement recommendations
- Designed and defined pattern libraries, style guides, UI/UX policies; software and hardware recommendations
- Collaborated with various teams to ensure consistency across products and corporate communications

#### **Experience 2020 - 1997**

- Valiant Solutions Director UI/UX, Woodbury NY
- Broadridge Financial Solutions Lead UI/UX Architect, Edgewood NY
- CA Technologies Web Developer, Islandia NY
- The Creative Group Web Designer/Developer, Rockville Center NY
- Veritas Laboratories Senior Designer / Developer / Project Manager, Bohemia NY
- Dowling College: Web Services Administrator, Oakdale NY
- theglobe.com Web Producer/Developer, Manhattan NY
- Channel21 Productions Webmaster/Technical Manager, Miller Place NY

### References

Available upon request